<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAC on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MAC on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Genome Medicine</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;figure2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium avium&lt;/i&gt; complex comprises the most frequent non-tuberculous mycobacteria in Europe. &lt;i&gt;M. chimaera&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;M. intracellulare&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;M. avium&lt;/i&gt; are clinically most relevant.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this new publication, we present a clinico-genomic dataset of more than 400 patients from Germany and Continental Europe. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/gm_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rdcu.be/dNhDe&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38982539/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and genomic features of Mycobacterium avium complex: a multi-national European study</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/gm_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/gm_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rdcu.be/dNhDe&#34;&gt;At Journal Homepage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38982539/&#34;&gt;At PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International MAC-PD cohort</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/mac-pd-cohort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/mac-pd-cohort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Wouter Hoerfsloot, Jakko van Ingen, Arthur Lemson (Nijmegen, Netherlands)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium avium&lt;/em&gt; complex (MAC) is the most frequent causative species that results in nontuberculous mycobacterial pulmonary disease (NTM-PD). Current treatment outcomes for MAC-PD are unsatisfactory with sputum culture conversion rates between 50-70%.The high prevalence of drug toxicity and low adherence to guideline-based treatment (GBT) are key reasons for the limited treatment success. Hence, there is an unmet need for prospective data on effectiveness of, adherence and adjustments to MAC-PD treatment regimens. By collaborating with NTM-NET and ESGMYC affiliated medical centers, we enable systematic, prospective data collection of an international MAC-PD cohort.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
International MAC-PD cohort enrolls MAC-LD patients starting antimycobacterial treatment into a prospective, international data-registry to assess the culture conversion rate after 6 months of antimycobacterial treatment, adverse drug reactions and treatment modifications.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.radboudumc.nl/en/radboudumc-community-for-infectious-diseases/our-expert-areas/mycobacterial-infectious-diseases&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
