<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MDR TB on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/tags/mdr-tb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MDR TB on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/tags/mdr-tb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No1Lost</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/no1lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/no1lost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PI: Ralf Otto-Knapp (Berlin)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The No1Lost project is a collaborative initiative funded by the  Federal Ministry of Health (BMG) of Germany,  involving the German Central Committee against Tuberculosis (DZK), the Justus Liebig University Giessen, and the foundation CAPNETZ STIFTUNG, with the aim of improving treatment adherence among tuberculosis (TB) patients in Germany.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Despite the availability of modern diagnostic and treatment options, TB remains one of the most deadly infectious diseases worldwide. While the number of cases of TB in Germany remains low, there has been an increase in cases among vulnerable risk groups, which require good interdisciplinary care. Despite the availability of effective treatment regimens, many patients fail to complete the treatment, particularly in cases of multidrug-resistant TB (MDR-TB).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The objective of the No1Lost project is therefore to conduct a comprehensive analysis of the care structures for tuberculosis in Germany in order to identify the underlying reasons for treatment discontinuation. The project aims to enhance interdisciplinary care and, through the provision of social-medical support, to facilitate adherence to treatment for individuals diagnosed with tuberculosis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dzk-tuberkulose.de/en/no1lost/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
