<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New projects launched</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to launch two novel projects:
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;TRACE-TB&lt;/b&gt;: The aim of this project is to evaluate biomarkers for the diagnosis of mycobacterial diseases. Existing diagnostic methods are often too slow, inaccurate or carry the risk of spreading infection, which makes early and specific treatment difficult. The TRACE-TB project therefore aims to validate promising biomarker candidates in different clinical cohorts. In addition, new markers are to be investigated using a proteomics approach.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;stride_tb.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;STRIDE-TB&lt;/b&gt;: This project aims to explore sex and gender differences in tuberculosis by systematically evaluating and summarizing the available evidence. It will focus on key aspects such as tuberculosis epidemiology, manifestation, covering both extrapulmonary and pulmonary tuberculosis, and treatment factors such as monitoring, duration, and outcomes like mortality and TB sequelae. The goal is to understand whether and how tuberculosis progresses differently between men and women, how treatment responses vary, and what the health consequences are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Genome Medicine</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Unlike &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/i&gt; complex, non-tuberculous mycobacteria can harbor plasmids. However, their role in virulence and pathogenesis remains largely uninvestigated.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this work, led by Dr. Margo Diricks, over 9000 genomic datasets of NTM were investigated regarding their plasmid content, the distribution of plasmids across species/subspecies/(sub)lineages, and the presence of virulence/resistance genes on detected plasmids.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/gm_2025&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genomemedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13073-025-01443-7&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40038805/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at ESCMID Global 2025 in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to present our work at this year&#39;s ESCMID Global in Vienna taking place 11-15 April 2025:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Preliminary results from Europe-wide survey “EURO-SURVERY TB” on adjunctive surgical treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P0671, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Sex-dependent variability of isoniazid and rifampicin serum levels in patients with tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P2437, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics of antibacterial drugs &amp; therapeutic drug monitoring (incl lab methods, models, in vitro and in vivo studies).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Pathogen and host determinants of extrapulmonary tuberculosis among 1035 patients in Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2008-2023&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P0555, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Recovery of non-tuberculous mycobacteria and detection of dominant circulating clones in indoor water samples from Germany&lt;/b&gt;, Margo Diricks, ePoster flash Session, 14/04/2025, 116:15 in Arena 2, New data in non-tuberculous mycobacterial disease.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Mycobacterium chelonae infection of a cardiovascular bioprosthesis linked to a recent outbreak&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P3946, 15/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Case reports and case series (n&lt;10).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We will be happy to see you there!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.escmid.org/congress-events/escmid-global/&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Clinical Microbiology and Infection</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;featured2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Are &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/i&gt; complex lineages predictors for extrapulmonary tuberculosis?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In our recent work, geographical origin and other host
determined factors such as female sex and age were stronger
predictors of extrapulmonary tuberculosis than Mtbc lineage.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to see this great collaboration between the Municipial Health Authorities (Gesundheitsamt) Frankfurt, the Research Center Borstel, the European Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (ECDC), Labor Dr. Limbach, and the University Hospital Frankfurt now published in CMI.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalmicrobiologyandinfection.com/article/S1198-743X(24)00535-4/fulltext&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39528087/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Infection</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;figure_2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Drug-sensitive TB (DS-TB) is treated with isoniazid, rifampicin, ethambutol, and pyrazinamide. Factors like fast-metabolizing enzymes, malabsorption, and drug interactions can influence serum drug levels. Current TB treatment guidelines recommend weight-adapted dosing without considering sex differences. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this study, we examine drug levels of isoniazid and rifampicin in TB patients treated between 2019 and 2023 at our center focusing on sex-specific aspects.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Interestingly, rifampicin levels were significantly lower in men compared to women, despite weight-adjusted dosing. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/infection_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s15010-024-02424-5&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39531129/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Genome Medicine</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;figure2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium avium&lt;/i&gt; complex comprises the most frequent non-tuberculous mycobacteria in Europe. &lt;i&gt;M. chimaera&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;M. intracellulare&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;M. avium&lt;/i&gt; are clinically most relevant.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this new publication, we present a clinico-genomic dataset of more than 400 patients from Germany and Continental Europe. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/gm_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rdcu.be/dNhDe&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38982539/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in the Journal of Infection</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;gr1.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium malmoense&lt;/i&gt; is a rare cause of NTM pulmonary disease. In this systemativ review and meta-analysis, we summarize the available clinical data of &lt;i&gt;M. malmoense&lt;/i&gt; infection from more than 800 patients. The pathogen is shown to be of high clinical relevance and macrolide or rifamycin containing regimens might improve survival in affected patients.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to see the result of this Danish-German collaboration finally published in the Journal of Infection.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/yjinf_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journalofinfection.com/article/S0163-4453(24)00137-3/fulltext&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38906266/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;figure_2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In collaboration with the Department of Radiology at University Hospital Frankfurt, we investigated the radiological features of patients infected or colonised with slow-growing non-tuberculous mycobacteria. We applied a score, originally described for MAC pulmonary disease, to other SGM-species. We are very happy that the manuscript has been accepted for publication in &lt;i&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/i&gt;, now.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/scirep_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-64029-0&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38858499/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful clinical tuberculosis symposium taken place</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;flyer_program.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The second Clinical Tuberculosis Symposium of the DGI section &#34;Mycobacterioses&#34; has taken place in Frankfurt. This joint event was organised by DGI, DZIF, DGP, DGPI, and DZK. More than 70 persons participated and learned about the newest evolutions in tuberculosis care and research. We are very happy to have had the opportunity to host this event at University Hospital Frankfurt, Department of Infectious Diseases.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Third round will take place in &lt;a href=&#34;https://denkglobaldx.org/&#34;&gt;Heidelberg&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
See you there!
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit (MIRU) online</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-miru&#34;&gt;Welcome to the MIRU&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We are happy to finally have launched our website. &lt;b&gt;miru.org&lt;/b&gt; is the homepage of our research group based at the University Hospital Frankfurt and in close cooperation with other collaborating centers. We investigate mycobacterial infections including tuberculosis and non-tuberculous mycobacterial infection with a variety of mehtods. On this site we will share ongoing projects, latest news and other relevant information.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Don&#39;t hesitate to get in touch!
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
