<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>whole genome sequencing on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/tags/whole-genome-sequencing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in whole genome sequencing on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/tags/whole-genome-sequencing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at ESCMID Global 2025 in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to present our work at this year&#39;s ESCMID Global in Vienna taking place 11-15 April 2025:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Preliminary results from Europe-wide survey “EURO-SURVERY TB” on adjunctive surgical treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P0671, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Sex-dependent variability of isoniazid and rifampicin serum levels in patients with tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P2437, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics of antibacterial drugs &amp; therapeutic drug monitoring (incl lab methods, models, in vitro and in vivo studies).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Pathogen and host determinants of extrapulmonary tuberculosis among 1035 patients in Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2008-2023&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P0555, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Recovery of non-tuberculous mycobacteria and detection of dominant circulating clones in indoor water samples from Germany&lt;/b&gt;, Margo Diricks, ePoster flash Session, 14/04/2025, 116:15 in Arena 2, New data in non-tuberculous mycobacterial disease.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Mycobacterium chelonae infection of a cardiovascular bioprosthesis linked to a recent outbreak&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P3946, 15/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Case reports and case series (n&lt;10).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We will be happy to see you there!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.escmid.org/congress-events/escmid-global/&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Clinical Microbiology and Infection</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;featured2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Are &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/i&gt; complex lineages predictors for extrapulmonary tuberculosis?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In our recent work, geographical origin and other host
determined factors such as female sex and age were stronger
predictors of extrapulmonary tuberculosis than Mtbc lineage.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to see this great collaboration between the Municipial Health Authorities (Gesundheitsamt) Frankfurt, the Research Center Borstel, the European Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (ECDC), Labor Dr. Limbach, and the University Hospital Frankfurt now published in CMI.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalmicrobiologyandinfection.com/article/S1198-743X(24)00535-4/fulltext&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39528087/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathogen and host determinants of extrapulmonary tuberculosis among 1035 patients in Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2008-2023</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalmicrobiologyandinfection.com/article/S1198-743X(24)00535-4/fulltext&#34;&gt;At Journal Homepage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39528087/&#34;&gt;At PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFMTBSEQ</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/ffmtbseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/ffmtbseq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In close collaboration with the muncipial health authorities, the Institute of Medical Microbiology and Infection Control at University Hospital Frankfurt, and the Research Center Borstel, our study group analyses epidemiological and sequencing data that has been generated as part of the PHIMS-TB study under the realms of the RKI.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Predictive factors for clinical phenotype, as well as transmission clustering are investigated. This includes the mycobacterial lineage, but also host-determined factors, such as geographical origin.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MYSTIC-NTM</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/mystic-ntm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/mystic-ntm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Margo Diricks, Nils Wetzstein&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
With increasing availability of genomic data for different species of non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) and standardized phenotypic drug susceptibility (pDST) data, the possibility of novel resistance gene predictions as well as application of known mechanisms to rare NTM species comes into reach.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
To date, genotypic prediction of drug susceptibility in NTM (gDST) is mainly limited to macrolides and aminoglycosides and only well established for M. abscessus, while extensive catalogues of mutational resistance in Mycobacterium tuberculosis complex have been established and are used in clinical practice.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The increased use of whole genome sequencing as well as the application of standardized methods for pDST might allow to overcome these shortcomings and facilitate the generation of an extensive database with linked gDST and pDST data for NTM.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We have the opportunity of generating a unique, large, international dataset of genotypic and phenotypic DST data. The study will include data from NTM isolates assessed in the respective laboratories. No clinical data and therefore no ethical consent will be needed. The submitted data can also be already published.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Inclusion criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bacterial isolate belonging to any NTM-species (clinical, zoonotic or environmental sample)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whole genome sequencing data for isolate available (short read or long read). The data can either be uploaded to a public repository (regardless of sequencing platform) or directly shared (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pDST data for isolate available: either SLOMYCO1, SLOMYCO2, RAPMYCO1, RAPMYCO2, potentially other methods
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How can the data be shared?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data (i.e. minimum inhibitory concentrations (MICS) and accession numbers of publicly available genome data) can be uploaded via a subsection of the NTMnet registry using a graphical user interface. Please contact the PIs to get an account and instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also send data (i.e. MICs, accession numbers or whole genome sequencing data in case these are not yet publicly available) via secure servers to one of the PIs. These secure servers can either be set up by your institution or the institution of one of the PIs of this study.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The long-term goals of this study will be:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal 1: to improve and extend current resistance catalogue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal 2: to provide a benchmark dataset for resistance prediction tools (e.g. NTMprofiler)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal 3: to improve surveillance and monitor trends
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why participate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because we all share the goal of improving the diagnosis and treatment of NTM infections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributors will be appropriately acknowledged in any resulting publications — either as co-authors or as part of the study group, depending on the extent of contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To ensure statistically meaningful correlations between genetic mutations and phenotypic resistance, broad participation and larger datasets are crucial — your contribution will help make this possible.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntmnet.org/mystic-ntm&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
