<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RGM on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/tags/rgm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RGM on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/tags/rgm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NTM-registry</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: In contrast to tuberculosis, infections due to non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) are not notifiable. However, there is accumulating evidence that their incidence is increasing in countries with low endemicity of tuberculosis. In addition, the pathogenicity of different NTM varies widely.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the epidemiological and clinical features of patients infected or colonised with non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: The ntmscope_registry will establish needed data collecting tools in a monocentric approach, after an initial test phase the registry will become available to additional centers with the aim of becoming the first NTM-registry in Germany. This is to be achieved with the Institute for Medical Informatics (IMI) of the Goethe University Frankfurt.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Registry currently being constructed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osse-register.de/&#34;&gt;www.osse-register.de&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTMscope-Eco</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/eco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/eco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) are recovered from a variety of environmental samples. In other countries, potable water, for example from shower heads, has been a frequent source. Patients with NTM-pulmonary disease have been shown to acquire their bacterial isolates from their household water samples in some cases. However, in Germany, NTM have not been isolated from water samples until now and only been found in soil, dust, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Isolation of NTM from water samples.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Environmental sampling, culture, molecular identification techniques.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Published&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTMscope-Meta</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/meta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Treatment and management of rare NTM remains a considerable challenge as randomized controlled trials or systematic studies are scarce. Most therapeutic recommendations are based on &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; data or clinical experience with more frequent NTM. The optimal therapy for most infections remains unclear.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of clinical data regarding the clinical manifestations and therapeutic outcomes of rare NTM.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Literature review, (individual patient data) meta analysis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Ongoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
