<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FFMTBSEQ on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/tags/ffmtbseq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FFMTBSEQ on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/tags/ffmtbseq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at ESCMID Global 2025 in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to present our work at this year&#39;s ESCMID Global in Vienna taking place 11-15 April 2025:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Preliminary results from Europe-wide survey “EURO-SURVERY TB” on adjunctive surgical treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P0671, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Sex-dependent variability of isoniazid and rifampicin serum levels in patients with tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P2437, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics of antibacterial drugs &amp; therapeutic drug monitoring (incl lab methods, models, in vitro and in vivo studies).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Pathogen and host determinants of extrapulmonary tuberculosis among 1035 patients in Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2008-2023&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P0555, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Recovery of non-tuberculous mycobacteria and detection of dominant circulating clones in indoor water samples from Germany&lt;/b&gt;, Margo Diricks, ePoster flash Session, 14/04/2025, 116:15 in Arena 2, New data in non-tuberculous mycobacterial disease.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Mycobacterium chelonae infection of a cardiovascular bioprosthesis linked to a recent outbreak&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P3946, 15/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Case reports and case series (n&lt;10).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We will be happy to see you there!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.escmid.org/congress-events/escmid-global/&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
