<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collaborations on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collaborations on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ALL POCUS TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/pocustb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/pocustb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Stefan Weber, Claudia Denkinger (Heidelberg)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is a prospective, cross-sectional multicentre cohort study in which the accuracy and the diagnostic yield of Tuberculosis-focused point-of-care ultrasound (POCUS) and image interpretation with artificial intelligence (AI) will be assessed in inpatients and outpatients with presumed TB disease in German and Indian sites. Dedicated POCUS protocols for the diagnosis of HIV-associated extra-pulmonary tuberculosis (EPTB) in high incidence settings have been proposed, but reliable accuracy data for both patients with and without HIV are thus far limited. Another arising ultrasound field with great potential is lung ultrasound (LUS) for the diagnosis and the assessment of disease extent for pulmonary TB. Our study ultrasound protocol will cover both abdominal and thoracic locations in both HIV(+) and HIV(-) patients. In addition, we will follow up patients with confirmed TB under anti-mycobacterial therapy to document the natural evolution of TB-associated sonographic findings and assess their value for monitoring of therapy success. With this study we want to fill this gap and to guide implementation efforts by better characterizing the sensitivity and specificity of sonographic findings for TB diagnosis against a comprehensive reference standard. POCUS has the potential to  increase TB case finding and avoid over-diagnosis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A study on the accuracy of point-of-care ultrasound for the diagnosis of thoracic and abdominal TB. We investigate the accuracy of both single tuberculosis associated findings as well as composite findings such as combinations of pathological changes. We are enrolling patients with presumed TB regardless of HIV-status and will perform subgroup analysis for patients with/without TB and patients with/without diabetes mellitus as possible risk factors. The aim is the description of possible combinations for a point-of-care protocol, which can be used as a non-sputum based triage test for TB. In addition, we evaluate patients longitudinally with ultrasound to determine the value for therapy monitoring for pulmonary and extrapulmonary findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://denkglobaldx.org/research/&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mexTB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/mextb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/mextb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Isabelle Suárez, Jan Rybniker (Cologne)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The mEX-TB study is a prospective, multicenter cohort and biomarker study aimed at improving the care of patients with extrapulmonary tuberculosis (EPTB).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
While pulmonary tuberculosis remains the most prevalent form of the disease, approximately 24% of tuberculosis cases diagnosed in Germany involve extrapulmonary organs, according to the 2023 RKI report. Diagnosing and treating EPTB may pose distinct challenges due to its varied clinical presentations, nonspecific symptoms, and paradoxical reactions during the course of treatment.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The goal of this three-year DZIF-funded study is to facilitate a biomarker-based treatment approach for EPTB patients. This will be achieved by identifying biomarkers associated with EPTB and determining risk factors that contribute to the development of EPTB. To achieve these objectives, clinical data and patient samples from EPTB patients are being systematically collected, analyzed, and evaluated at six DZIF study sites in Germany: Bonn, Borstel, Frankfurt, Hamburg, Heidelberg, and Cologne.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The study, conducted under the leadership of DZIF researchers Priv.-Doz. Dr. Isabelle Suárez and Prof. Dr. Jan Rybniker at the University Hospital Cologne (UHC), aims to contribute to the improved diagnosis and treatment of EPTB not only in Germany but worldwide. It is a continuation of the monocentric DZIF-funded pilot study (EX-TB study) that has been running at UHC since 2018.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://innere1.uk-koeln.de/forschung/klinische-studien/studienregister/studienregister-details/studienregister/mex-tb-study-4940/Tuberkulose/show-StudyConfig/?cHash=69c330473b4130a5157a53cb0788cd55&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrant-sensitive care and tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/migrant_sensitive_care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/migrant_sensitive_care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Lorenzo Guglielmetti, Berit Lange, Heinke Kunst&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The aim of the study is to assess whether migrant-sensitive care strategies lead to an increase of successful active TB and LTBI treatment outcomes in migrants.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A retrospective cohort study including all TB and LTBI patients seen/a random sample (depending on clinical centers availability of data and data entering resources) of TB and LTBI patients seen between 2013 and 2018 will be performed, with the following objectives:
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Proportion and characteristics (including clinical presentation) of migrant TB patients (any patient not born in country of residence, differentiated by region of origin, length of stay in country, type of migration and flight route [see also attached data collection tool on patient characteristics]) over all TB (RR-TB and DS-TB) and LTBI patients including trends over time will be assessed (Aim 1).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Management strategies and operational parameters of centers recruiting TB and LTBI migrant patients will be described according to their applicability to migrant needs and differences in management and operational parameters of health care units will be described (see also attached data collection tool on center characteristics) (Aim 2).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
TB treatment outcomes (WHO and simplified) and LTBI treatment completion in non-migrants and different migrant groups will be described and compared between centers and the influence of migrant-sensitive management strategies on individual TB treatment outcomes and LTBI treatment completion and difference between migrant and non-migrant treatment outcomes/treatment completion over time will be analyzed accounting for potential confounders and effect modifiers such as different group of migrants, comorbidities and adverse reaction to drugs (Aim 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbnet.eu/projects&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
