<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TB on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</title>
    <link>https://miru-ffm.org/tags/tb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TB on Mycobacterial Infection Research Unit</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miru-ffm.org/tags/tb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at ESCMID Global 2025 in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to present our work at this year&#39;s ESCMID Global in Vienna taking place 11-15 April 2025:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Preliminary results from Europe-wide survey “EURO-SURVERY TB” on adjunctive surgical treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P0671, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Sex-dependent variability of isoniazid and rifampicin serum levels in patients with tuberculosis&lt;/b&gt;, Raja Idris, P2437, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics of antibacterial drugs &amp; therapeutic drug monitoring (incl lab methods, models, in vitro and in vivo studies).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Pathogen and host determinants of extrapulmonary tuberculosis among 1035 patients in Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2008-2023&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P0555, 13/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Tuberculosis and other mycobacterial infections (incl epidemiology, clinical, diagnostics, antimycobacterial drugs, susceptibility testing, treatment &amp; prevention).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Recovery of non-tuberculous mycobacteria and detection of dominant circulating clones in indoor water samples from Germany&lt;/b&gt;, Margo Diricks, ePoster flash Session, 14/04/2025, 116:15 in Arena 2, New data in non-tuberculous mycobacterial disease.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Mycobacterium chelonae infection of a cardiovascular bioprosthesis linked to a recent outbreak&lt;/b&gt;, Nils Wetzstein, P3946, 15/04/2025, 12:00 - 13:30 in Poster Area in Hall D, Case reports and case series (n&lt;10).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We will be happy to see you there!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.escmid.org/congress-events/escmid-global/&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Clinical Microbiology and Infection</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;featured2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Are &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/i&gt; complex lineages predictors for extrapulmonary tuberculosis?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In our recent work, geographical origin and other host
determined factors such as female sex and age were stronger
predictors of extrapulmonary tuberculosis than Mtbc lineage.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We are very happy to see this great collaboration between the Municipial Health Authorities (Gesundheitsamt) Frankfurt, the Research Center Borstel, the European Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (ECDC), Labor Dr. Limbach, and the University Hospital Frankfurt now published in CMI.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalmicrobiologyandinfection.com/article/S1198-743X(24)00535-4/fulltext&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39528087/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostic Accuracy of Lung and Abdominal Ultrasound for Tuberculosis in a German Multicenter Cohort of Patients With Presumed Tuberculosis Disease</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/ofid_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/ofid_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/ofid/article/11/12/ofae651/7919638?login=false&#34;&gt;At Journal Homepage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39691283/&#34;&gt;At PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication in Infection</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;figure_2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Drug-sensitive TB (DS-TB) is treated with isoniazid, rifampicin, ethambutol, and pyrazinamide. Factors like fast-metabolizing enzymes, malabsorption, and drug interactions can influence serum drug levels. Current TB treatment guidelines recommend weight-adapted dosing without considering sex differences. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this study, we examine drug levels of isoniazid and rifampicin in TB patients treated between 2019 and 2023 at our center focusing on sex-specific aspects.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Interestingly, rifampicin levels were significantly lower in men compared to women, despite weight-adjusted dosing. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can find the paper here, at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/publication/infection_2024&#34;&gt;miru-ffm.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s15010-024-02424-5&#34;&gt; the journal&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39531129/&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathogen and host determinants of extrapulmonary tuberculosis among 1035 patients in Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2008-2023</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/cmi_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalmicrobiologyandinfection.com/article/S1198-743X(24)00535-4/fulltext&#34;&gt;At Journal Homepage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39528087/&#34;&gt;At PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex-dependent variability of isoniazid and rifampicin serum levels in patients with tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/infection_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/infection_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s15010-024-02424-5&#34;&gt;At Springer&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39531129/&#34;&gt;Pubmed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful clinical tuberculosis symposium taken place</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/news/post2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;flyer_program.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The second Clinical Tuberculosis Symposium of the DGI section &#34;Mycobacterioses&#34; has taken place in Frankfurt. This joint event was organised by DGI, DZIF, DGP, DGPI, and DZK. More than 70 persons participated and learned about the newest evolutions in tuberculosis care and research. We are very happy to have had the opportunity to host this event at University Hospital Frankfurt, Department of Infectious Diseases.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Third round will take place in &lt;a href=&#34;https://denkglobaldx.org/&#34;&gt;Heidelberg&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
See you there!
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occurrence of extrapulmonary tuberculosis is associated with geographical origin: spatial characteristics of the Frankfurt TB cohort 2013-2018</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/infection_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/publication/infection_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s15010-022-01921-9&#34;&gt;At Springer&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36181634/&#34;&gt;Pubmed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALL POCUS TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/pocustb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/pocustb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Stefan Weber, Claudia Denkinger (Heidelberg)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is a prospective, cross-sectional multicentre cohort study in which the accuracy and the diagnostic yield of Tuberculosis-focused point-of-care ultrasound (POCUS) and image interpretation with artificial intelligence (AI) will be assessed in inpatients and outpatients with presumed TB disease in German and Indian sites. Dedicated POCUS protocols for the diagnosis of HIV-associated extra-pulmonary tuberculosis (EPTB) in high incidence settings have been proposed, but reliable accuracy data for both patients with and without HIV are thus far limited. Another arising ultrasound field with great potential is lung ultrasound (LUS) for the diagnosis and the assessment of disease extent for pulmonary TB. Our study ultrasound protocol will cover both abdominal and thoracic locations in both HIV(+) and HIV(-) patients. In addition, we will follow up patients with confirmed TB under anti-mycobacterial therapy to document the natural evolution of TB-associated sonographic findings and assess their value for monitoring of therapy success. With this study we want to fill this gap and to guide implementation efforts by better characterizing the sensitivity and specificity of sonographic findings for TB diagnosis against a comprehensive reference standard. POCUS has the potential to  increase TB case finding and avoid over-diagnosis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A study on the accuracy of point-of-care ultrasound for the diagnosis of thoracic and abdominal TB. We investigate the accuracy of both single tuberculosis associated findings as well as composite findings such as combinations of pathological changes. We are enrolling patients with presumed TB regardless of HIV-status and will perform subgroup analysis for patients with/without TB and patients with/without diabetes mellitus as possible risk factors. The aim is the description of possible combinations for a point-of-care protocol, which can be used as a non-sputum based triage test for TB. In addition, we evaluate patients longitudinally with ultrasound to determine the value for therapy monitoring for pulmonary and extrapulmonary findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://denkglobaldx.org/research/&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DisTB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/distb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/distb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PI: Michael Hölscher (Munich)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Researchers from Fraunhofer ITMP and the Tropical Institute at LMU Klinikum launched the &amp;ldquo;DisTB&amp;rdquo; study(Discovery of novel biomarkers for the diagnosis of TB disease) at the Fraunhofer ITMP site for Immunology, Infection and Pandemic Research IIP in Penzberg/Munich.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Blood-based test methods such as the interferon-gamma release assay, IGRA for short, have already existed for several years, but it is not possible to differentiate between active tuberculosis disease and a latent tuberculosis infection or previous contact with the bacterium.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The aim of the study is to identify new, highly sensitive and specific biomarkers for the diagnosis of tuberculosis disease that are not based on sputum, but on blood, urine or saliva samples. In addition, a platform for the collection of samples for the discovery and verification of further diagnostic markers is to be created.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lmu-klinikum.de/tropical-institute/news-and-press/news-items/tuberculosis-closing-the-diagnostic-gap/21ab3a374fd36661&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECMO-TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/ecmo_tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/ecmo_tb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuberculosis can cause extensive lung damage leading to respiratory insufficiency. However, data on treatment outcome and clinical course of ECMO therapy in patients with tuberculosis is scarce due to low case numbers.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of clinical data regarding clinical course and outcome of patients with ECMO therapy and tuberculosis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Literature review, (individual patient data) meta analysis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Published&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFMTBSEQ</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/ffmtbseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/ffmtbseq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In close collaboration with the muncipial health authorities, the Institute of Medical Microbiology and Infection Control at University Hospital Frankfurt, and the Research Center Borstel, our study group analyses epidemiological and sequencing data that has been generated as part of the PHIMS-TB study under the realms of the RKI.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Predictive factors for clinical phenotype, as well as transmission clustering are investigated. This includes the mycobacterial lineage, but also host-determined factors, such as geographpical origin.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LEVEL-UP-TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/leveluptb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/leveluptb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tuberculosis therapy is usuallay administered in weight adapted doses. However, factors like fast-metabolizing enzymes, malabsorption, and drug interactions can influence their serum drug levels. This is not yet taken into account as part of the clinical routine or therapeutic guidelines.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The LEVEL-UP-TB project evaluates different factors predicting serum drug levels of antimycobacterial therapy as well as their influence on therapeutic outcome.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/#contact&#34;&gt;Contact PI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mexTB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/mextb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/mextb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Isabelle Suárez, Jan Rybniker (Cologne)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The mEX-TB study is a prospective, multicenter cohort and biomarker study aimed at improving the care of patients with extrapulmonary tuberculosis (EPTB).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
While pulmonary tuberculosis remains the most prevalent form of the disease, approximately 24% of tuberculosis cases diagnosed in Germany involve extrapulmonary organs, according to the 2023 RKI report. Diagnosing and treating EPTB may pose distinct challenges due to its varied clinical presentations, nonspecific symptoms, and paradoxical reactions during the course of treatment.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The goal of this three-year DZIF-funded study is to facilitate a biomarker-based treatment approach for EPTB patients. This will be achieved by identifying biomarkers associated with EPTB and determining risk factors that contribute to the development of EPTB. To achieve these objectives, clinical data and patient samples from EPTB patients are being systematically collected, analyzed, and evaluated at six DZIF study sites in Germany: Bonn, Borstel, Frankfurt, Hamburg, Heidelberg, and Cologne.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The study, conducted under the leadership of DZIF researchers Priv.-Doz. Dr. Isabelle Suárez and Prof. Dr. Jan Rybniker at the University Hospital Cologne (UHC), aims to contribute to the improved diagnosis and treatment of EPTB not only in Germany but worldwide. It is a continuation of the monocentric DZIF-funded pilot study (EX-TB study) that has been running at UHC since 2018.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://innere1.uk-koeln.de/forschung/klinische-studien/studienregister/studienregister-details/studienregister/mex-tb-study-4940/Tuberkulose/show-StudyConfig/?cHash=69c330473b4130a5157a53cb0788cd55&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrant-sensitive care and tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/migrant_sensitive_care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/migrant_sensitive_care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIs: Lorenzo Guglielmetti, Berit Lange, Heinke Kunst&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The aim of the study is to assess whether migrant-sensitive care strategies lead to an increase of successful active TB and LTBI treatment outcomes in migrants.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A retrospective cohort study including all TB and LTBI patients seen/a random sample (depending on clinical centers availability of data and data entering resources) of TB and LTBI patients seen between 2013 and 2018 will be performed, with the following objectives:
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Proportion and characteristics (including clinical presentation) of migrant TB patients (any patient not born in country of residence, differentiated by region of origin, length of stay in country, type of migration and flight route [see also attached data collection tool on patient characteristics]) over all TB (RR-TB and DS-TB) and LTBI patients including trends over time will be assessed (Aim 1).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Management strategies and operational parameters of centers recruiting TB and LTBI migrant patients will be described according to their applicability to migrant needs and differences in management and operational parameters of health care units will be described (see also attached data collection tool on center characteristics) (Aim 2).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
TB treatment outcomes (WHO and simplified) and LTBI treatment completion in non-migrants and different migrant groups will be described and compared between centers and the influence of migrant-sensitive management strategies on individual TB treatment outcomes and LTBI treatment completion and difference between migrant and non-migrant treatment outcomes/treatment completion over time will be analyzed accounting for potential confounders and effect modifiers such as different group of migrants, comorbidities and adverse reaction to drugs (Aim 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbnet.eu/projects&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No1Lost</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/no1lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/collaboration/no1lost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PI: Ralf Otto-Knapp (Berlin)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The No1Lost project is a collaborative initiative funded by the  Federal Ministry of Health (BMG) of Germany,  involving the German Central Committee against Tuberculosis (DZK), the Justus Liebig University Giessen, and the foundation CAPNETZ STIFTUNG, with the aim of improving treatment adherence among tuberculosis (TB) patients in Germany.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Despite the availability of modern diagnostic and treatment options, TB remains one of the most deadly infectious diseases worldwide. While the number of cases of TB in Germany remains low, there has been an increase in cases among vulnerable risk groups, which require good interdisciplinary care. Despite the availability of effective treatment regimens, many patients fail to complete the treatment, particularly in cases of multidrug-resistant TB (MDR-TB).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The objective of the No1Lost project is therefore to conduct a comprehensive analysis of the care structures for tuberculosis in Germany in order to identify the underlying reasons for treatment discontinuation. The project aims to enhance interdisciplinary care and, through the provision of social-medical support, to facilitate adherence to treatment for individuals diagnosed with tuberculosis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dzk-tuberkulose.de/en/no1lost/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STRIDE-TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/stride_tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/stride_tb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project aims to explore sex and gender differences in tuberculosis by systematically evaluating and summarizing the available evidence. It will focus on key aspects such as tuberculosis epidemiology, manifestation, covering both extrapulmonary and pulmonary tuberculosis, and treatment factors such as monitoring, duration, and outcomes like mortality and TB sequelae. The goal is to understand whether and how tuberculosis progresses differently between men and women, how treatment responses vary, and what the health consequences are.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SURVERY-TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/survery_tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/survery_tb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuberculosis can cause extensive lung damage. This might contribute to prolonged therapies and adverse outcomes. In some patients, adjunctive therapy might be useful. However, there are no large studies and the landscape of existing experience regarding surgery in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis is limited.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: To draw a detailed picture on existing experience of the usage of adjunctive surgery in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Survey of health professionals.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Survey ongoing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScuRXMYVdY122eXSkMqKjSIj8r3pgfXvcY-dkK0-XOunE-WaQ/viewform&#34;&gt;Participate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRACE-TB</title>
      <link>https://miru-ffm.org/project/trace_tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miru-ffm.org/project/trace_tb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project is to evaluate biomarkers for the diagnosis of mycobacterial diseases. Existing diagnostic methods are often too slow, inaccurate or carry the risk of spreading infection, which makes early and specific treatment difficult. The TRACE-TB project therefore aims to validate promising biomarker candidates in different clinical cohorts. In addition, new markers are to be investigated using a proteomics approach.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://miru-ffm.org/contact/&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
